Middle States Accreditation Reports; Collection ua931
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection1952-2010
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Middle States Association of Colleges and Schools. Commission on Higher Education
ua931
0.66 cubic ft.
The collection is made up of the accreditiation reports for the University at Albany.
Administrative History
Collection is made up of the accreditation reports from the Middle States Association of Colleges and Schools. One of the many functions performed by this group was the accreditation of Universities and colleges to maintain their quality of learning and maintain their status. This group performed these reports until 2013 when their Commission on Higher Education broke off and created its own insititution exclusively committed to the accreditation of colleges.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the accreditation reports dating from the years 1952-2010. The information in these reports pertains to evaluaitons of the degree programs, the physical campus, and the other facilities. This gives a depicition of the school as far back as 1952.
Arrangement of the Collection
Collection is arranged in chronological order.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Accreditation (Education); Education - Standards; UAlbany Reference Collections; State College for Teachers (Albany, N.Y.); State Univeristy of New York at Albany; Middle States Association of Colleges and Schools
- Middle States Accreditation Reports, 1938 (Box 1 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 1)
- Middle States Accreditation Reports, 1952 (Box 1 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 2)
- Middle States Accreditation Reports, 1961 (Box 1 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 3)
- Middle States Accreditation Reports, 1971 (Box 1 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 4)
- Self-Study Report for the Middle States Accreditation Reports, 1971 (Box 1 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 5)
- Middle States Accreditation Reports, 1980 (Box 1 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 6)
- Self-Study Report for the Middle States Accreditation Reports, 1980 (Box 1 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 7)
- Middle States Accreditation Review, 1980 (Box 1 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 8)
- Middle States Accreditation Reports, 1990 (Box 1 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 9)
- Middle States Accreditation Self-Study Report: 1990-2000 (Box 2 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 1)
- Middle States Accreditation Self-Study Report: 1990-2000 Appendices (Box 2 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 2)
- Middle States Accreditation Reports, 2000 (Box 2 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 3)
- Middle States Accreditation Reports Copy, 2000 (Box 2 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 4)
- Middle States Accreditation Self-Study Report Chapter 1-6, 2010 (Box 2 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 5)
- Middle States Accreditation Self-Study Report Chapters 7-13, 2010 (Box 2 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 6)
- Reply of President Philip to Middle States Report, 2010 (Box 2 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 7)
- Report of Middle States Evaluation Team, 2010 (Box 2 (Middle States Accreditation Reports Collection), Folder 8)